Guide to the Alvah Bessie Papers ALBA.024
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series IV: Subject Files, 1936-1985
  - Correspondence: Watt, George, 1984-1985 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Cowley, Malcolm: "Lament for the Abraham Lincoln Brigade," Published in the Sewanee Review, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Film Proposal: "A Valley in Spain," by Ray Perez, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Franco and the Jews: Book Proposal with Introduction and Outline (Author Unidentified), undated (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Geiser, Carl: Trip to Spain: Notes on Archival Research and Battle Sites, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Hecht, Joseph: Transcribed World War II Letter, Photocopies of Purple Certificates and Photograph, 1944-1945, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Hemingway, Ernest: Letter to Milton Wolff (typed copy), 1940 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - International Brigade: Fortieth Anniversary Conference in Florence, Oct 1976 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Joint Anti-Fascist Refugee Committee: Correspondence between Edward Barsky and Sumner Welles, 1943 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Rolfe, Edwin: "Elegia" (Inscribed copy), 1950 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Rosenstone, Robert: Inscribed Reprints and Correspondence, 1967-1968 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Spain: Opus Dei, 1971, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Spain: Carabanchel 10: Petition to Franco, undated (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Spain: Clippings, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Spain: Clippings, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Spain: Clippings, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Spain: Clippings, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Spain: Clippings, 1984-1985 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Spain: Politics: Essays and Articles, 1971-1979 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Spanish Civil War: Barcelona University Colloquium, Apr 1979 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Spanish Civil War: Battle of the Ebro: Fortieth Anniversary, Aug 1978 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Spanish Civil War: Massachusetts Institute of Technology Colloquium Agenda, May 1969 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Spanish Civil War Symposium: Dartmouth College, Apr 1981 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Tisa, John: Recalling the Good Fight: Promotional Material, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - "To Die in Madrid" (Documentary): Promotional Material, Correspondence, Clippings, 1965-1966 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Veterans: Combat and Medical Personnel: Contact Sheets, undated, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - VALB: Anniversary Commemorations: Fiftieth, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - VALB: Anniversaries and Events: Leaflets, Programs and Clippings, 1978-1985 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - VALB: Bay Area Chapter, 1979-1985 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - VALB: Clippings, 1980-1985 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - VALB: Correspondence, undated, 1977-1985 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - VALB: Leaflet: Edward Barsky and Milton Wolff Lecture, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - VALB: Promotional Campaign for Heart of Spain, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - VALB: Reagan, Ronald, 1984-1985 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - VALB: Tribute to Alvah Bessie (Thirty-Ninth Anniversary Dinner), Feb 1975 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - VALB: Veterans Rights Committee: Pamphlet, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 18)